A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, officers' diaries, RG 12, F-L FA392
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Hackett, Lewis W., 0.99 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes, 1 half-letter document box, and 3 microfilm boxes (35mm)
  - 1946, Hackett, Lewis Wendell (1884-1962); Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; 266 pages (Reel M Hac 2, Frame 584, Box 189)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. The diary documents the day to day build up to revolution, civil war and political strife in South America. The diary includes photographs and extracts of staff member diaries.
    Yellow fever; Bolivia; Argentina; Chile; Brazil; Trinidad; United States; Diaries; Public health; South America; Hookworm disease; Hygiene; Malaria; Medicine -- Research; DDT (Insecticide); Dominican Republic; Ecuador; Peru
  - 1947, Hackett, Lewis Wendell (1884-1962); Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; 278 pages (Reel M Hac 3, Frame 1, Box 189)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. The diary details the IHD projects in Mexico such as the Vera Cruz studies. The DDT programs for South America are outlined. Communicable Disease Programs are documented. Updates from staff member diaries are included as well as photographs. Hackett attended the Meeting of the Directing Council of the Pan-American Sanitary Organization in Buenos Aires, Sept. 24-Oct. 2, 1947, and the 16th National Congress of Hygiene in Brazil.
    Medicine -- Research; Medical education; Mexico; Hookworm disease; Yellow fever; Malaria; Hygiene; Brazil; Argentina; Panama; Peru; Diaries; DDT (Insecticide); Communicable diseases; Cholera; Chile; South America; Typhus fever; United States; Venezuela; Public health; Public health nursing; Sanitation; Smallpox
  - 1948, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell (1884-1962); 295 pages (Reel M Hac 3, Frame 280, Box 189)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. The diary documents civil and political unrest in South America, updates from staff member diaries, and outlines various DDT programs. Hackett attended the UNESCO conference, the APHA meeting and an IHD Regional Staff Conference. Included in this diary are photographs and a hand drawn map of Bolivia entitled "Areas to be Covered by the Division of Epidemiology and Control of Rural Endemic Diseases."
    Medicine -- Research; Peru; Malaria; Medical education; Public health nursing; Plague; Public health; Argentina; Brazil; South America; Smallpox; Ecuador; Hygiene; DDT (Insecticide); Yellow fever; United States; Uruguay; Syphilis; Typhus fever; Diaries
  - 1949, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell (1884-1962); 317 pages (Reel M Hac 3, Frame 575, Box 190)
    Organized according to interview and visit, Hackett discusses projects and proposals with professionals in the field of public health. He is involved in the progress of the RF programs, development of new projects and financing current and future research. Hackett assess various tropical diseases in South America and the local response to these outbreaks. He surveys and tours various health facilities, laboratories and medical schools. Hackett continues to assist in the creation of local South American public health infrastructure. Hackett attends Interdivisional Conference on Population Problems, and an APHA meeting. Documentation on the DDT experiments is included as well. Includes photographs, a map entitled, "Plague Regions in Bolivia", a map entitled, "Bolivia Distribution of Malaria." Included also are updates and excerpts from RF staff member diaries.
    England; Ecuador; DDT (Insecticide); Communicable diseases; Chile; Argentina; Medical education; United States; Typhus fever; Malaria; Leprosy; Diaries; Ireland; Hookworm disease; Hepatits; France; Syphilis; Smallpox; Tuberculosis; Nutrition; Medicine -- Research; Plague; Peru; Public health; Population; Sanitation; Public health nursing; Uruguay; Yellow fever
  - 1950, Rockefeller Foundation. International Health Division; Hackett, Lewis Wendell (1884-1962); 10 pages (Reel M Hac 3, Frame 892, Box 190)
    A brief 10 page diary with notes on the Sardinian Malaria campaign.
    Italy; Malaria; Medicine -- Research; Public health; Diaries
- Haddow, Alexander J., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1942-1950 (Box 191)
- Hahn, Richard G., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1939-1952 (Box 191)
- Hansens, Elton J., 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - 1943 (Box 191)
- Hanson, Frank B., 1.37 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes, 1 half-letter document box, and 3 microfilm boxes (35mm)
  - 1930-1931, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 263 pages (Reel M Han 1, Frame 1, Box 192)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. The diary details his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. Included is an index by place titled "Contents."
    Botany; Bulgaria; Austria; Biology -- Research; Netherlands; Latvia; Poland; Physics; Sweden; Russia; Wales; Switzerland; Diaries; Zoology; Italy; Ireland; Greece; Germany; France; Europe; Denmark; Chemistry
  - 1932, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 142 pages (Reel M Han 1, Frame 276, Box 192)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants.
    Switzerland; Russia; Sweden; Hungary; Germany; Physics; Netherlands; Chemistry; Finland; Europe; Zoology; Botany; Diaries; Biology -- Research
  - 1933 September 4-December 26, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 58 pages (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 459)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. Hanson is now an Assistant Director of the RF Natural Sciences program. The emphasis of the program is beginning to shift towards biological research. Hanson surveys University of Iowa, Cornell, Jackson Memorial Laboratory and the University of Virginia. He attends a meeting of drosophila workers.
    Zoology; United States; Biology -- Research; Physics; Botany; Diaries; Chemistry
  - 1934 January 8-April 30, Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation; 130 pages (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 518)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States and Canada to survey their current research. Hanson attends a symposium on heavy water.
    Botany; Biology -- Research; Diaries; Physics; Chemistry; Canada; Zoology; United States
  - 1934 May 1-December 31, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 134 pages (Reel M Han 1, Frame 652, Box 192)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. Hanson attends the Summer Meeting of the Genetics Society of America at Woods Hole and the AAAS Pittsburgh Meeting.
    Diaries; Botany; Biology -- Research; United States; Physics; Chemistry; Zoology
  - 1935 January 4-June 28, Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation; 97 pages (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 811)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus of the program is moving towards experimental biology. Programs from previous years are still open and active.
    Diaries; Zoology; United States; Physics; Chemistry; Botany; Biology -- Research
  - 1935 July 3-December 23, Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation; 163 pages (Box 192, Reel M Han 1, Frame 908)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus of the program is moving towards experimental biology. Programs from previous years are still open and active. Hanson attends a spectroscopic conference and surveys Woods Hole a former program investing in oceanographic work at sea.
    Zoology; United States; Physics; Oceanography; Chemistry; Botany; Biology -- Research; Diaries
  - 1936 January 1-April 30, Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation; 128 pages (Reel M Han 2, Frame 24, Box 192)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries records his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus of the program is moving towards experimental biology. Hanson attends an AAAS meeting and the Meeting of the American Association of Anatomists.
    Zoology; Physics; Physiology; Genetics; Mathematics; Endocrinology; Diaries; Biology -- Research; Chemistry
  - 1936 May 4-December 31, Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation; 135 pages (Reel M Han 2, Frame 152, Box 193)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus of the program is moving towards experimental biology. Hanson attends an AAAS meeting and the Meeting of the American Association of Anatomists.
    Mathematics; Netherlands; Endocrinology; Genetics; Chemistry; Biology -- Research; Physiology; Diaries; Physics; Zoology; United States
  - 1937, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 243 pages (Reel M Han 2, Frame 306, Box 193)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. Hanson attends the International Symposium on Early Man, Conference on Eugenics and Education, an AAAS meeting, and the Symposium on Biophysics of the American Institute of Physics.
    Physiology; Physics; Eugenics; Endocrinology; Mathematics; Genetics; Diaries; Biophysics; Biology -- Research; Chemistry
  - 1938, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 149 pages (Reel M Han 2, Frame 565, Box 193)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior.
    Chemistry; Biology -- Research; Physics; Physiology; United States; Zoology; Endocrinology; Genetics; Diaries; Nutrition; Bergmann, M. (Max) (1886-1944)
  - 1939, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 248 pages (Box 193, Reel M Han 2, Frame 735)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. Hanson tours Woods Hole for their marine biology program and attends a "Growth" Conference. The diary also details a cotton cellulose project under Dr. Cameron at the University of North Carolina and tobacco projects at Duke University.
    Endocrinology; Genetics; Nutrition; Physics; Biology -- Research; Botany; Chemistry; Cotton; Zoology; United States; Tobacco; Physiology; Bergmann, M. (Max) (1886-1944)
  - 1940 January 3-June 28, Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation; 140 pages (Reel M Han 3, Frame 20, Box 193)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. Hanson takes a "Western Trip" to visit universities in the western United States. He attends the Conference on Physical, Physical-Chemical and Organic Chemical Evidence Regarding Crystalline Protein Molecules, and the American Physical Society Session on "Optical Methods for the Study of Molecular Structure"
    Physiology; Physics; Nutrition; Genetics; Zoology; Diaries; Endocrinology; Chemistry; Biology -- Research
  - 1940 July 1-December 31, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 110 (Reel M Han 3, Frame 164, Box 194)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. Hanson tours Woods Hole's marine biology laboratory.
    Diaries; Chemistry; Biology -- Research; Genetics; Nutrition; Embryology; Endocrinology; Zoology; Physics; Physiology
  - 1941 January 3-May 31, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 136 pages (Box 194, Reel M Han 3, Frame 296)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. Hanson attends the Second Conference of the General Nutrition Committee of North Carolina.
    Embryology; Endocrinology; Chemistry; Physics; Physiology; Genetics; Nutrition; Zoology; United States; Diaries; Biology -- Research
  - 1941 June 2-December 30, Rockefeller Foundation; Hanson, Frank B.; 125 pages (Reel M Han 3, Frame 433, Box 194)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. Hanson attends the Meeting of the Mexican Agricultural Commission, and the Meeting of the Chesapeake Bay Fisheries Committee. The diary also includes notes "Possible Lines of Approach to an Evaluation of the Present Status and Future Possibilities of Agriculture in Mexico."
    Nutrition; Genetics; Physiology; Physics; Zoology; United States; Diaries; Biology -- Research; Agriculture; Chemistry; Endocrinology; Embryology
  - 1942, Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation; 181 pages (Box 194, Reel M Han 3, Frame 585)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus on experimental biology has narrowed to focus on the avenue of nutrition. The diary includes a Stenographic Report of the Meeting of the Advisory Committee for Mexican Agriculture of the Rockefeller Foundation.
    United States; Zoology; Diaries; Chemistry; Biology -- Research; Agriculture; Physiology; Physics; Nutrition; Mexico; Genetics; Endocrinology; Embryology
  - 1943, Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation; 183 pages (Reel M Han 3, Frame 781, Box 194)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus on experimental biology has narrowed to focus on the avenue of nutrition. Hanson attends a meeting of the Chesapeake Bay Fisheries Commission and visits Woods Hole marine biology laboratory.
    Zoology; Diaries; Physiology; Agriculture; United States; Biology -- Research; Nutrition; Chemistry; Physics; Endocrinology; Embryology; Genetics
  - 1944, Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation; 183 pages (Box 194, Reel M Han 3, Frame 987)
    Organized according to visit and interview, entries for this year record the meetings and conversations that took place between Hanson, professionals and students in the field of natural sciences. Entries record his tours of various laboratories, discussions of research and impressions of fellowship applicants. He tours various universities in the United States to survey their current research for the RF program in experimental biology. The present program of the division of natural sciences of the RF aims to assist in the understanding of behavior. The focus on experimental biology has narrowed to focus on the avenue of nutrition. Hanson attends Meeting Committee of Advisors on Mexican Agriculture, Conference to Discuss the Derriengue Problem in Mexico, Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission Meeting of Committee on Education, and the AAAS meetings.
    Agriculture; Diaries; Zoology; United States; Physiology; Nutrition; Physics; Endocrinology; Genetics; Embryology; Biology -- Research; Chemistry
  - Index, 1933 September 4-1934 December 31; Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Han 1, Frame 439, Box 195)
  - Index, 1935; Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Han 1, Frame 787, Box 195)
    1935 Index; 24 pages.
    indexes (reference sources); Chemistry; Botany; Biology -- Research; Zoology; United States; Physics
  - Index, 1936; Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation (Box 195, Reel M Han 2, Frame 1)
    1936 Index; 23 pages.
  - Index, 1937; Hanson, Frank B.; Rockefeller Foundation (Reel M Han 2, Frame 287, Box 195)
    1937 Index; 17 pages.
    Physics; Physiology; United States; Eugenics; Genetics; indexes (reference sources); Mathematics; Endocrinology; Chemistry; Biophysics; Biology -- Research